go by example I have been hearing about
go by example for years uh I've never
met Mark or Eli they look like wonderful
people uh however I have heard from
people who have learned go for the first
time by using go by example one of them
is the primary contributor to the the
Bonsai project and his go code is
some of the best C code I've ever seen
he has a natural understanding he
extremely pantic about his go cat and he
has helped me realize things about go
like for example not necessarily putting
an argument identifier if you're not
using it um uh inline uh type casting
and a couple of things that I and the
use of uh tagged modules as long as you
put a prefix so you can have model of
three post these are all things that
taught me that he had discovered
and BEC because his first experience
with go was go by example I decided to
give it another look and to be fair I
looked at go by example
in
20 19 or something like when it first
came out and it it didn't really impress
me at the time uh of course the there's
always been a real drought of resources
online and now there's like seems like
there's a plethora of resources online
most of which are either overly
complicated go 101 right I'm looking at
you or or or or or teach you bitwise
mathematics even though you're an
absolute beginner and expect you to
already know C that would be you tur ofo
which by the way has dropped off as it's
not even getting supported anymore even
though it's listed on the front page and
then there's all of the books right
there's go and action which is really
really outdated and has big bugs in it
there's um you know I had to write an
AATA for my school when I did that one
there's the book from Donovan the K andr
people that wrote you know the kir book
which is ancient there's the there's uh
the other book that doxy the go you know
what is it the Caleb doxy book which is
ancient it covers go like 1.2 there's
there's the head first go which covers
go one 7 they're so old so it's really
hard to know where to go no pun intended
to learn go and go by example as of this
day what is the day I don't even know
but as of this day Monday November 18th
at 8:31 p.m. go by example is my single
biggest recommendation for learning go
if you know how to code if you don't
know how to code you're going to be lost
going to be lost and people I am working
as fast as I can to make a resource that
teaches computer programming computer
science with go to absolute beginners
who don't even know what a variable is
other than in math I'm working because
that that resource doesn't exist and if
you want to help me uh contribute or
feed it feedback and read the book as
I'm writing it I'm using a lot of AI for
that I'm doing it online you know plug
for that if you want to help me with
that if you want to help me with the
Bonsai project create but if you're
looking to learn go fast and you already
learned the code in JavaScript or python
probably or maybe Java then you should
use go by example and this is a big
thank you to Mark and Eli I am going to
actually work through this a little bit
and I want to show you something that I
didn't see it took me a full day to
realize this and everybody on the stream
is making fun of me because I didn't see
it right
away I did a huge spiel about hey if you
want to make your name in the world you
should make a PR you should work the
project and make a PR that allows you to
run these examples in the really amazing
go
playground at least one of you out there
knows what I'm talking about can you see
it on the screen here let's take a
moment to look at the screen is it
possible that such a thing already
exists I downloaded the entire source
code and still missed
it so so maybe you waited in this video
you're watching you a lot of you sign
off of the video early it's like okay
use go by go by example good got it I'm
out of here but for the few of you who
are waiting until this part of the video
let me show you something very amazing
you can click on this little blob of an
icon and it will actually take the code
into the extremely amazing go playground
and within the go play if you're an
educator if you're an educator this is
amazing if you're an educator you're
probably stuck teaching AP Computer
Science God help you go watch my video
on college board but but you know you
can click on run right here and you can
run it something that's really cool
about the go playground too is you can
click over here and you can actually
change whatever version of go you want
by the way don't learn any version of go
before
1.19 go 1 Point there's there is the
world of go before 1.19 and there's the
world of go after 1.19 and some would
argue that was something similar 1.13 is
when they brought in
modules people people don't use any go
older than 1.19 unless you have a
mandated requirement to do so there is
just so much about the language that's
changed gotten better most notably
generics but also the any untyped
interface a bunch of things that make
computer programming much easier
especially if you're teaching or you're
learning it for the first time this is
the playground you can go play with it
in the playground you can modify it you
can check out whether a thing is going
to work or not and oh thank you for the
sub that was very nice well way now
Watson has actually just made their
first PR against the Bonsai project
thank you it's very timely sub I
appreciate you doing that um and by the
way I encourage you to come on in I've
got plenty of work for you if you want
to help do minor contributions to the
Bonsai or big ones while you're learning
go I have projects that you can
contribute to if you want to with very
specific help wanted things so you can
put your name out there on on an open
source contribution that's not
insignificant it's not some help do you
know which is always needed but you know
so anyway this is not about that this is
about the go by examples tool and I want
to just tell you so so the go by example
tool albeit really plain and simple is
plain and simple and that's what makes
it so great it's so easy to get bogged
down by all of the you know the the the
pain and suffering of this right that
the one negative I would say is that
because it is so plain and simple it
kind of lacks that you know pneumonic
device appeal that has been
scientifically proven to help you
remember things better I'm talking about
head first and by the way the author of
head for first go I forget his name is
amazing he's one of the most amazing
authors I've ever read I wish we could
get him to write an updated version of
headfirst go for go 1.23 I have read
that there is a new version in the works
for head first go I am praying for that
because that would be handed hands down
the best possible thing that you could
possibly have and so here we go go is an
open source programming language
designed to build scale blah blah here's
the official documentation here's your
first example and then it continues to
have all of these very basic things
varic functions closures recursion even
gets into generics and go routines and
and what I find so amazing about this is
just how simple it is it's like it
doesn't it's not it's not trying to sell
you on anything it's not trying to give
you the Demonic device like my book is
where it makes turns everything into a
spell right but it like is just simple
and it's really fun so here we go here
we have like a function we're going to
do that function here and there are a
couple of things that I find wrong about
it so there for let me give you a couple
of examples of things that I don't like
and so I did notice that there is a use
of the it seems that most of these
examples have not been updated for 1.19
and advanced after that most notably the
use of the of the empty interface it's
called so you can actually see this
there you anytime you see in the code
you see an interface with uh I'm trying
to find one
here I'm trying to find
it where are you where where have you
gone I can't find you now I don't know
where it is but if you see there's so
there's a thing called any which is much
easier to use now I'm not seeing it here
I was impressed that they do have forn
in range which is how you iterate over
integers that that is not something
covered by most books even though it's
very useful um they I'm still trying to
find the untyped interface I mean the
empty interface array idea maybe it's
down here in closur functions I mean the
concept this is a good example of why
this isn't good for beginners the idea
of closure is has it's very hard for
beginners to understand in my experience
go supports Anonymous functions with the
form closures that's it right and I
guess they made a link to what it is on
Wikipedia so you can go read about
it that is probably not the most you
know Exposition about what that is and
why I would use it um I mean I guess I
guess they tried to focus on just
teaching you the principles and letting
you go learn about what a closure is so
if you're an absolute beginner let's
actually amend what I said about not
using this it's possible if you're I
mean it's possible I don't know I
haven't sent anybody I can't make a
comment on this but if you're an
absolute beginner who doesn't know
anything about programming the
simplicities of these examples might be
enough to help you learn about that so
let's let me so in the autodidactic
approach to learning if you're going to
go by examples that assumes you know how
to code already and you're reading the
explanation which is ultra Ultra simple
and is using words you should know from
programming like closure you might be
able to use that and you might be able
to say okay what is a closure and you
can go read about closure and you can
read about the computer science
principles that are in each of these
examples as you go so that you can
supplement your your learning about go
with a a broader learning about what
computer science is and how to program
that is a very likely possibility if you
do that by the way please let me know I
really want to know who has never coded
before or who can actually learn how to
code by going through go by example and
my my intent by creating uh code
Wizard's First spell book learn computer
science and program practical
programming with go as a first language
is the same thing essentially is these
examples except for the examples are
spells and they have been put into a
spell form so with pretty pictures and
stuff so that you can associate you know
the setting of a variable for example by
by you know putting a rabbit in a hat
and then pulling the rabbit out of the
hat and putting a pigeon in the Hat you
know and those kind of those neonic
devices but you might not want that you
might be a non-nonsense kind of person
who just wants just give me the stuff
and that and then they're like okay well
this is how you do a thing but why would
I do that thing right and you can kind
of imply the the reasons for that and
that um and a lot of this stuff if
you're just starting out learning how to
code you just be doing little things in
your code book until you figure out how
to make something bigger and then it
would be more of a go get you know go
get the examples and stuff like that um
so that's all I'm going to say about go
by example but have a look at it and and
and by the way uh if you happen to be
the goby example people I strongly
encourage you to kind of accept some of
those PRS it looks like your project
just hasn't been updated in like three
months so I almost forked the project
and did some of those PR requests and
added some stuff to it I I don't intend
to do that but if if there's no
attention to this repo over the next
three or four months I I might do that
and if you need help please let me know
if you need somebody to help manage the
project um i' I'd be happy to to help
submit some PRS right now though you
have almost a dozen PRS that have had no
attention that are fixing things that
you need to have fixed so please take a
look at it otherwise I'm not going to be
able to recommend it or I'm going to
Fork it and just make my own version of
it